

## **PROFILE**

As a Mechanical Engineer I got to know the world of programming and found a passion there, in fact I think that for a long time I already liked programming, for this reason I decided to learn to program, in addition to the fact that I have a Systems Technician. I am currently learning Software Development and I am visualizing myself in the Backend area. I have knowledge and I am getting stronger in JAVA, OOP Object Oriented Programming, a bit of Python and C Language. Version management with Git and GitHub. Additionally, I also have knowledge of HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap5, SASS. Of course, also, I have been learning about agile methodologies like SCRUM.

I am a versatile person, who likes to acquire new experiences in different areas that contribute to my human and professional development.

## **CONTACT**

PHONE: (+57) 314-575-1351 EMAIL:

victorvalencia.725@gmail.com

#### **HOBBIES**

Academy Photography Practice sports Sudoku

#### **REFERENCES**

- Mateo Zapata
   Software engineering- EPAM
   System.
   Phone: +57 3046303885
- Dahián Valencia
   Doctor and surgeon,
   Neurology Resident –
   Universidad de Antioquia.
   Phone: +57 3046626247

# VICTOR DANIEL VALENCIA RÍOS

Software Developer Junior. Mechanical Engineer.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Oracle

May, 2022 – August, 2022 Java programming.

#### Pontificia Universidad JAVERIANA

September, 2021 – March, 2022

Diploma in Coding and Programming. Samsung Innovation Campus.

### University of Michigan

August, 2021 – October, 2021 Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python).

#### Universidad de Antioquia

March, 2013 – September, 2019 Mechanical Engineering.

Thesis: Thermal and emission diagnosis of a boiler and design of the control system for combustion optimization.

#### SFNA

January, 2011 – November, 2012 Sistems technique.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Compañía de Galletas NOEL [Operator TPM]

November, 2019 - At present

Make focused improvements with previous analysis of processes and performance and result indicators. Also fulfill the other functions as operator of the Operational Excellence Model.

## Universidad de Antioquia [Mechanical engineering intern]

January, 2019 - July, 2019

Completion of degree work "Thermal and emission diagnosis of a boiler and design of the control system for combustion optimization."

## Industria de Alimentos Zenú [Mechanical engineering intern]

June, 2018 - December, 2018

Maintenance information analyst assistant.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Emotional intelligence
- Resilient
- Collaboration and teamwork
- Patience Skills
- Communication
- Time management
- Problem solving skills
- Attention to detail

# **HARD SKILLS**

- Basic Object-Oriented Programming.
- JAVA
- Basic Python
- Basic C Language
- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap V5, SASS
- Git, GitHub
- SCRUI
- Mathematical, rational and analytical aptitude
- English B1